<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Felwig Software</title>
 <link href="http://felwig.com//atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://felwig.com//"/>
 <updated>2013-10-11T21:43:49+01:00</updated>
 <id>http://felwig.com/</id>
 <author>
   <name>Felwig Software</name>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>First screenshots!</title>
   <link href="http://felwig.com//posts/first-screenshots%21"/>
   <updated>2013-10-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://felwig.com//posts/first-screenshots!</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;float:center;height:30px&quot; src=&quot;/images/teasers/teaser-1.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Somehow 6 months has passed since we first posted to this blog.  In that time we have been coding, drawing, writing, rewriting and playing &lt;em&gt;fork&lt;/em&gt;, but we haven&amp;rsquo;t written anything about it.  Now that the engine is largely finished, the content is taking shape, and we are beginning to plan for a beta of the first 3 levels, the time has come to go on the record about &lt;em&gt;fork&lt;/em&gt; with our first set of screenshots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/1-shooting.png&quot; alt=&quot;shooting at spiders&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see &lt;em&gt;fork&lt;/em&gt; is a platformer at heart, albeit one set on curved planets floating in space.  To get around you need your ship, shown performing a rather hazardous landing in this screenshot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/1-landing.png&quot; alt=&quot;landing in progress&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst flying, &lt;em&gt;fork&lt;/em&gt; is reminiscent of Atari&amp;rsquo;s classic, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lunar_Lander_(arcade_game&quot;&gt;Lunar lander&lt;/a&gt;, but then you land, jump out your ship, grab your gun and the game becomes a platformer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/1-landed.png&quot; alt=&quot;landed&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t always need your ship to move around though, here our hero (also unnamed as yet) is jumping from one asteroid to the next as he moves about his home village.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/1-asteroids.png&quot; alt=&quot;asteroids&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is less apparent from these pictures is that, in the tradition of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Link%27s_Awakening&quot;&gt;Zelda&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cave_story&quot;&gt;Cave Story&lt;/a&gt;, the levels are set in a large world, and form scenes in an overarching story, revealed as you explore this world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference is that whereas in Zelda and Cave story, the over world is quite separate from the levels, in &lt;em&gt;fork&lt;/em&gt; you jump back in your ship, takeoff and seamless fly to the next stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/1-chat.png&quot; alt=&quot;your little brother&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, a glimpse at our ice planet.  The renderer is in progress, but it shows you the variety we are aiming for in &lt;em&gt;fork&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;s world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/1-ice.png&quot; alt=&quot;ice planet&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Welcome back to Felwig Games</title>
   <link href="http://felwig.com//posts/welcome"/>
   <updated>2013-04-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://felwig.com//posts/welcome</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;float:center;height:30px&quot; src=&quot;/images/teasers/teaser-2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After almost 3 years of inactivity, Felwig games is reborn.  We are working hard on our new space platformer &amp;ndash; for now codenamed &lt;em&gt;fork&lt;/em&gt;.  Join our hero as he jumps in his spaceship and heads off around his galaxy to find out why his star is dying.  The game moves seamlessly from a 360 degree space shooter to a platform game as you land your ship on a planet and set off exploring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finishing our first game, the Elite inspired &lt;a href=&quot;ple.com/us/app/firmament/id383706668?mt=8&quot;&gt;Firmament&lt;/a&gt;, life became busy for the two of us, so other than Boxel, a fun 3D match-3 game for &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/boxel/id441537386?mt=8&quot;&gt;iPad&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/boxel-sd/id449504741?mt=8&quot;&gt;iPhone&lt;/a&gt;, we have released nothing.  This period of inactivity has not been entirely idle, in fact we toyed with three or four proof of concept projects in that time, but until &lt;em&gt;fork&lt;/em&gt; none inspired us to take them beyond the prototype stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The focus of this blog will of course be the development of &lt;em&gt;fork&lt;/em&gt; as we work towards a closed beta, a public beta and eventual release, but we will also use it to discuss indie development in general through the lens of this project.  A later post will have screenshots and far more detail on &lt;em&gt;fork&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;s gameplay and progress towards beta. At heart fork is an adventure platformer with the gameplay tied to a story, similar in concept to Cave Story and the 2D Zelda games.  It is the story of a young man setting off to discover why his planet&amp;rsquo;s sun is dying, and how can he save his solar system.  If you want  to be one of our beta testers then watch this space, or better still, get in touch &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#x6c;&amp;#116;&amp;#x6f;&amp;#x3a;&amp;#x66;&amp;#101;&amp;#x6c;&amp;#x77;&amp;#x69;&amp;#103;&amp;#64;&amp;#x67;&amp;#x6d;&amp;#97;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#46;&amp;#99;&amp;#x6f;&amp;#x6d;&quot;&gt;&amp;#x66;&amp;#x65;&amp;#x6c;&amp;#x77;&amp;#105;&amp;#x67;&amp;#x40;&amp;#103;&amp;#x6d;&amp;#x61;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#46;&amp;#99;&amp;#x6f;&amp;#x6d;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
